avira.de 2015-12-28

# Privacy policy

Avira (“we,” “us,” “our,” or “Avira”) strives to protect your privacy at all times. Avira, a leading expert in the IT security field known for protecting you against malware, viruses and other digital threats, makes protecting your personal data a top priority. If you are located in the United States or Canada, Avira means Avira, Inc., 330 Primrose Avenue, Suite 610, Burlingame, CA 94010, USA. If you are located outside the United States or Canada, Avira means Avira Operations GmbH & Co. KG, Kaplaneiweg 1, 88069 Tettnang, Germany.

By reviewing and accepting this privacy policy and using Avira’s products and services, you expressly understand and consent that Avira may possibly collect, save and use certain data about your computer, smartphone or tablet (“Device”) and its interaction with other Devices, which may include its identification number, IP address, location, contents, language settings, IMEI code, brand, model, battery level, hardware model, operating system version, telephone number, SIM number, network provider, memory status and geographical information based on the GPS/Wi-Fi network position. We may also gather personally identifiable information (“PII”) including, but not limited to your, name, address, phone number, email address, credit card information and other information that can be used to identify you.

The purpose of this privacy policy is to provide you with more information about the specific manner in which we collect, save, use and share data when you visit our website and/or use our products and services. Additionally, we will explain how we use PII, Cookies (as described in more detail and defined below) and analytics tools throughout our website and across our products and services. We do not share data (including PII) with third parties in a manner inconsistent with this privacy policy or privacy laws (which may require you to provide express consent).

## Products and Services

### Avira Protection Cloud, Avira URL Cloud and Avira ProActiv

Avira has integrated the Protection Cloud, URL Cloud and Avira ProActiv (“ProActiv”) features into its products to protect you from threats even more effectively. These features allow us to analyze new or unknown programs from potentially hazardous sources in real time. We use these features only for security purposes to provide you with the best possible Avira products and services. When Protection Cloud security and Avira ProActiv are enabled, our products use certain integrated rules to determine whether one or more events on your system can be attributed to a virus or malware attack. Avira analyzes viruses and malware in its virus laboratory and, based on the results, creates these rules. Based on your system’s behavior, our products can detect whether your system is currently being attacked by a virus or malware and can initiate effective countermeasures. Such countermeasures may include sending a "digital fingerprint" of an unknown or suspicious executable file to Avira in real time. Avira analyzes the transmitted "fingerprint" and immediately returns a status message helping to determine whether the file is clean or malware. Under certain circumstance it may be necessary to transmit the executable file to Avira for further analysis. In this event, files are exchanged between your computer/device and the Protection Cloud in encrypted form. No personal files (formats such as .pdf, .doc and .xls) or personal documents (such as photos and videos) are transferred. Data is only used for malware analysis and is not forwarded to third parties. Refer to our [Protection Cloud site](http://www.avira.com/en/avira-protection-cloud) and our [ProActiv site](http://www.avira.com/en/proactiv) for more details. Our URL Cloud feature helps identify URLs that are harmful to your system when you are browsing the web. URL Cloud is able to analyze the URLs you visit and determine which URLs may be malware, spam and/or phishing and warn you about such URLs before you proceed. While we interact with the sites you input via a particular product in order to provide this feature, we always remove any and all PII and any other information is stored for a short period of time and subsequently deleted.

### Your Avira account

In order to activate and/or use some of our products or services, you will need to create an Avira-specific account (“Account”). During the process of setting up your account, we will ask you for PII such as your email address. We need this information to allow you to activate or manage the Avira products and services you use. We may associate your email address and other PII (such as name and address) with your account and access of our products or services. For further information, please see the User Experience and Statistics section below.

### Facebook Connect and Google+ Sign-In

For some web-based services or functions of our products and services (for example, the login via [https://my.avira.com](https://my.avira.com/)) we offer a log in via Facebook Connect or Google+ Sign-In. Facebook Connect is a service of Facebook, Inc. (“Facebook”) and Google+ Sign-In is a service of Google, Inc. (“Google”). The use of Facebook Connect or Google+ Sign-In is subject to the respective Facebook and/or Google privacy policies and terms of use. When using Facebook Connect, your Facebook profile and public data available on Facebook will be transferred from Facebook to Avira. When using Google+ Sign-In, your Google+ login information data (which may contain PII such as your name, email address, phone and other information you have entered as part of your Google+ profile) will be transferred from Google to Avira. To find out more information about Facebook Connect, please click [here](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info-on-other) and/or review the Facebook Connect login pop-up. To obtain more information about Google+ Sign-In and how to manage your Google+ access rights, please click [here](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/3466521?rd=1).

With respect to either Facebook Connect or Google + Sign-In, Avira processes and stores your transmitted data (potentially containing PII), for the purpose of registering you with the web-based services or functions of our products and services.

By logging in via Facebook Connect and/or Google+ Sign-In, you consent to either Facebook and/or Google transferring data (potentially containing PII) to Avira, as well as, the transmission of your data from Avira to Facebook and/or Google.

If you do not agree to such a data transfer, please use your Avira Account as a login instead of Facebook Connect and/or Google+ Sign-In.

### Inviting others to use our products or services     **            **

You may be able to invite a friend or family member to try some of our products and services by sharing an invitation via email, Facebook, Twitter or Google+.  To use the email invite feature, you will have to enter your friend or family member’s email address (which is PII). Please do not use this function without each and every respective friend’s family member’s consent as Avira will send your invitation to use our products or services to the email address you entered. This email invitation will contain your PII (including your name and the email address you entered into your Account). If you choose to share the invitation via Facebook, Twitter or Google+, you will need to log into each service with the applicable account information and we will interface with the respective API in order to share a link inviting your friend or family member to try our products and services.

### Manage a family member of friend´s device through the Avira dashboard

Some of our products and services (such as https://my.avira.com) offer a feature allowing you to invite your friends or family members to have you monitor and/or manage their devices through your Avira dashboard. You will be able to monitor and/or manage your friends’ and family members’ devices once such individuals accept the invitation you send through the dashboard.

Once your friend or family member installs our product or service, you will see the individual within your dashboard and may have access to each person’s account information including: name and email address, photo (if it is uploaded), type of device used, the products or services the individual installed and the status of each device, including whether there are any security issues (e.g. a virus). In the event of a security issue, you will be able to contact your friend or family member with relevant information by sending a message via your dashboard. Both you and your friend or family member can choose to remove their device(s) from your dashboard at any time and your friend or family member’s device(s) will no longer be visible in your dashboard.

If you allow someone to monitor and/or manage your device(s) via the Avira dashboard, you expressly agree to grant them access to your device(s) in the manner described above.

### Applications on mobile devices

Certain product features intended to protect you, such as the anti-theft feature of our Android or iOS product, require that you grant Avira permission to access the location data associated with your particular device.

The Avira Identity Guard product accesses your address book in order to inform you when and if any of your contacts have had their information compromised as part of an external data breach. Pursuant to the requirements of the Android and iOS platforms, we will only gather such information and have access to your address book if you grant us permission to do so (in the manner required by the respective mobile platform). Every time you utilize this product, we check the information in your address book against a database of known email addresses that have been breached. If we find a match, we will inform you and give you the option to pass this information on to a particular contact. We do not store your address book data on our servers long-term. The only information we store is if you dismiss one of our warnings.

## Website

You can visit most areas of the Avira website without disclosing any personal information. Avira only logs the domain name, IP address and browser type of our website's visitors via our web server log files and analytics tools at irregular intervals. We use this information to log global access to our website.

However, for certain features that you may want to use, we will ask that you provide Avira the necessary information to run such products and services. You can decide at any time whether you would like to continue with an instruction prompting you to provide PII. In some cases, you will be unable to complete a particular step in the process if you do not want to provide the information requested. For example, we will ask for PII in the following instances:

  * If you place an order with our contract partner "cleverbridge AG" through our online store, we will ask you to provide information required for processing the order (for example, your name, address, credit card number or bank details and your email address).
  * If you use our online technical support or ask questions about our products and services using the contact form or the contact options on our website, we will ask you to give us PII required for processing the support request. This can include your email address, name and address, as well as information about your computer hardware and software and the type of problem that occurred.
  * If you have requested a test license on our website, in order to activate such license, you may have to provide PII, such as an email address.
  * If you request a service from us via our website.
  * If you participate in a survey on our website.
  * If you subscribe to a newsletter. If you signed up for a newsletter and no longer want to receive it, you can unsubscribe at any time by using the unsubscribe option provided in the email or by sending us an email using the contact information provided below.

### Use of Cookies

Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer or in your browser which are loaded on your browser during your initial use of a particular product or service and do not include any data identifying you personally (“Cookie” or “Cookies”). Cookies may be used, for example, to identify the browser you are using so that our website displays properly. We also use Cookies in various places on our website in order to document your visit to the Avira website and allow for a more efficient website design (for instance, the shopping cart feature used for ordering in the Avira online store). If you do not want to allow Avira or a respective third party to use Cookies, you can disable Cookie installation via your browser setting. While you also have the option of deleting Cookies from your computer's hard disk at any time, if you choose to do so, you may be unable to use all of the features of our website, products and services.

### Avira’s Safe Search

We currently host our own search via [https://safesearch.avira.com](https://safesearch.avira.com/). We collect and store certain information if you use this product including the search query, the browser and operating system you use to conduct the search, your IP address and the type of search conducted. We may aggregate certain data associated with how users perform searches (for example, how many web searches were made in a particular day or in a particular region), but will not share any PII or non-pseudynomized data we collected with any third parties. This search is hosted and stored on Avira’s servers, however we use third parties in order to provide you the search results and such third-party providers may collect PII as fully described below.

## User Experience and Statistics

We use our own proprietary technologies (including soft authentication systems, storage and messaging engines, databases and big data repositories) in order to perform statistical evaluations using pseudonymized user profiles to optimize your experience with our products and provide relevant content and advertisements. If you utilize multiple email addresses to access your Avira account, we may tie those emails to one profile. We may combine information we gather about your use of one product or service with your use of another product or service

We also use the information we collect to offer you content that is more tailored to your needs so that we can provide you with more relevant search results and advertisements. We believe more relevant advertising provides a better Internet experience. This is also how we support our business while still providing certain products or services to you free of charge. As part of this process, we may collect information about how you use and interact with the advertisements that we offer to you and the manner in which you use our products and services across various Devices. Based on this Device-specific information (for example, the hardware model, operating system, version device identifies, mobile network information including your phone number) and the unique application number assigned to some of our products and services, we may be able to compile a personal profile about you.

When you log in and access your Account or our products, we may automatically collect and store certain information such as the details of how you use our products, what kind of search queries you conduct, where your computer is routing from, your browser type and version, and Cookies that may identify your browser and/or account. By reviewing and accepting this privacy policy, you understand and agree that we may combine  non-PII or pseudonymized data obtained via our proprietary soft authentication systems with PII obtained when you sign up for an Avira account. We do not share this combined data with third parties.

In addition to our own proprietary technology, we do use the following third-party tools for marketing purposes and to make your visit to our website and/or use of our products/services a more user-friendly experience:

### 1\. Adobe Analytics (Omniture)

We use Adobe Analytics software from Adobe Systems, Inc. ("Adobe"). It uses Cookies and tracking pixels either stored or retrieved from your computer/device and also makes it possible to analyze your use of our website. This process collects and saves data that we use to create use profiles based on pseudonyms. These profiles are used to analyze visitor behavior and improve our offerings and design based on user needs. Without your expressly granted and formal consent, use profiles based on pseudonyms are not merged with personally identifiable information that we may have received from you in a different context. Adobe does not process your IP address and only saves it in truncated form. Adobe transfers the information collected within the EU and stores it on its EU servers. At any time, you can opt out of Adobe collecting and storing your data by following the instructions in the link below:

More information about Adobe System’s privacy policy and its data privacy policies is available [here](http://www.adobe.com/en/privacy.html).

### 2\. Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics, a web analysis service from Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses Cookies to make it possible to analyze your use of our website. Information about your use of our website the Cookie generates is usually transferred to a Google server in the USA and saved there. However, before this happens, Google shortens and anonymizes your IP address (Google's anonymizeIp process) if located within a member state of the European Union or in other contracting member states to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. The entire IP address is transferred to a Google server in the USA and saved there only in exceptional cases. This anonymization ensures that your IP address cannot be traced back to you. Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website in order to compile reports about website activities for Avira and provide additional services associated with website and Internet usage. Google can transfer this information to third parties, where appropriate, if legally mandated or if Google contracts with third parties to process such data. Google will not associate your IP address with other Google data. By using our website, you expressly consent to Google’s collection and storage of your data in the manner and for the purposes described above.

You also have the option to prevent Google from acquiring and processing data generated by Cookies and data related to your use of our website (including your IP address) by downloading and installing a Google-provided browser plugin.

More information about Google Analytics can be found [here](https://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html).

### 3\. CrazyEgg

We use the CrazyEgg tool, a web analysis service from Crazy Egg, Inc. ("CrazyEgg"). CrazyEgg uses Cookies to analyze your use of our website. This process collects and saves data that we use to create use profiles based on pseudonyms. These profiles are used to analyze visitor behavior and improve our offerings and design based on user needs. Without your expressly granted and formal consent, use profiles based on pseudonyms are not merged with personally identifiable information that we may have received from you in a different context. Information about your use of our website (including your IP address) Cookies generate is transferred to a CrazyEgg server in the US and stored there. CrazyEgg will use this information to compiles reports about activities on and use of our website and provide additional services associated with website and Internet use.

You can opt out of CrazyEgg collecting and storing your data at any time by following the instructions in the link below:

More information about the software and CrazyEgg’s privacy policy can be found [here](http://www.crazyegg.com/privacy).

### 4\. Mixpanel

Additionally, Avira uses technologies from Mixpanel, Inc. ("Mixpanel") within some of our products to carry out statistical evaluations allowing Avira to continuously improve and optimize product features and make their designs more appealing.  Mixpanel uses Cookies to detect your browser type, operating system, language settings, the search criteria that you enter and your IP address and then send such data to a Mixpanel server in the USA. Mixpanel anonymizes your IP address and only the anonymized IP address is sent to Avira, ensuring that your privacy remains protected. If you do not want to consent to such data collection, please see our instructions for disabling Cookies in the website-related section below. Furthermore, you can opt out of Mixpanel collecting and storing such data at any time by following the instructions in the link below:

More information about Mixpanel and its privacy policy can be found [here](https://mixpanel.com/privacy/).

## Additional Information

### Sharing information with third parties

Avira does not forward PII to third parties (including for marketing purposes or for selling or renting addresses) without your formal consent (which may be obtained during the installation process for a particular products). One exception to this policy is contractual relationships with service providers and affiliated companies that we engage to process data on our behalf. Service providers and affiliated companies are contractually obligated to adhere strictly to data protection legislation, treat your PII confidentially and use it only for providing service and transacting business on our behalf. We only transfer the PII that is necessary to achieve a specific purpose. For example, for supplying products via the online store, Avira works together with cleverbridge AG, Brabanter Str. 2-4, 50674 Cologne, Germany to provide you with a convenient option for ordering and paying via the Internet. Avira uses the cleverbridge AG services for shipping products, processing orders, invoicing and payments. As we are a multi-national corporation, we may store and process your personal information on a server outside the country where you live if we have a data processing agreement in place allowing us to do so.

The search functions Avira provides (<https://safesearch.avira.com/> or <http://avira.search.ask.com/>, for example), are provided by APN, LLC (Ask.com). If you start a search query via the search functions, Ask.Com records certain information and displays the search results. For example, Ask.com determines your IP address, the source of your search, your browser and platform type and your language settings. Ask.com can forward this information to third-party content providers and sponsored links. For more information and to see Ask.com’s privacy policy, please click [here](http://about.ask.com/privacy-policy/).

Provided we are complying with privacy laws, we may share non-PII with our partners (including publishers and advertisers and their respective sites). Such information may allow them to target advertising that is tailored to you. We require our advertising partners to comply with the applicable law and our privacy policy. However, our advertising partners may still collect data about your visit to a respective site via a particular advertisement including, but not limited to, placing Cookies on your browser, reviewing the number of times you viewed an advertisement, tracking what kind of search queries you conduct, where your computer is routing from and your browser type and version. We do not have control over the types of information such partners collect and how they will, ultimately, use it. We strongly recommend that you review any advertising partner’s privacy policy before clicking on a particular advertisement.  

Additionally, if an advertising partner requests that you provide any PII in order to allow you access to a particular site which you reached via its advertisement, that partner’s use and collection of the information will be governed by the advertising partner’s own privacy policy. Again, we recommend that you review any advertising partner’s privacy policy before providing such partner with any of your PII.

Finally, Avira may disclose your personal information if Avira is obligated to disclose it to governmental authorities, courts or other authorities due to legal regulations.

### Protecting PII

To protect your PII, we have taken safety precautions that comply with applicable data protection laws, this privacy policy and international information security standards. These procedures give us the ability to protect your data from misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, loss, tampering or deletion. For example, PII, such as your credit card information, is transmitted via the online store of our partner cleverbridge AG in encrypted form using the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) procedure.

Additionally, all personnel employed at Avira that have access to PII have been trained, taught and are obliged to treat your PII appropriately and in compliance with the requisite laws and regulations.

### Viewing, correcting, blocking and deleting PII

You have the right to view, correct, block or delete the PII Avira stores at any time. To do so, refer to the contact options specified in the contact information section below.

### Public information

Note that information you send to a forum, such as <http://forum.avira.com/wbb/> or [https://answers.avira.com](https://answers.avira.com/), is classified as public information and is not subject to this privacy policy. When communicating via such channels, there is a risk that others will find and use the information you submit. Therefore, be careful and handle your personal information in a responsible manner while online in a public forum.

## Contact information

If you have questions or comments, we will provide information about the PII we store upon your request, free of charge and without delay. Such information can also be sent electronically upon request.

Contact us at:

Avira  
Data Protection Officer  
Kaplaneiweg 1  
88069 Tettnang  
Germany  
Phone: +49 7542/500-0  
Email: [privacy@avira.com](mailto:privacy@avira.com)

Version: August 2014
